Dunham Family Papers, 1814-1951
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Dunham Family Writings, [see also "Writings" under individuals and Oversize Material - Scrapbook of writings by EKD and CD, Jr.]
  - Family magazine - "The Phoenix"
    - Series III, 1886-88 (Box 10, Folder 10-21)
- Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr. (1860-1922)
  - Biographical
    - Biographical summary, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Clippings including obituaries, 1892, 1918, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Tributes: printed pamphlet by Henry Osborne Taylor, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Simon Flexner, and Henry D. Dakin plus separate copies of each, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, [see also Mary (Dows) Dunham: correspondence and other material relating to Edward Kellogg Dunham, boxes 21-23] (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Writings, personal
    - Diary, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Play - "An experiment," undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Verses, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1877, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, family
    - Beatrice Dunham, 1876-95 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Carroll Dunham, Jr., 1895, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., 1914 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Harriet (Kellogg) Dunham, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1894-96, undated (Box 11, Folder 17-20)
    - Amelia Nash (Kellogg) Henshaw, 1895, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Other family, 1894, 1896-97 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, general
    - Dr. William H. Flint (regarding MDD's pregnancy), 1895 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Various friends, 1893, 1895-96, 1914, 1916-17, 1919, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Business correspondence, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 25)
      [see also Edward Kellogg Dunham: scrapbook of correspondence and memorabilia, box 15]
  - Correspondence, professional
    - William C. Baisted (Surgeon General, U.S. Navy), 1917-18 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Charles A. Jacobson, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Charles Lynch, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - James F. Mitchell (from army hospitals in France & the U.S.), 1918 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Alexis V. Moschcowitz, M.D., 1918, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - William Henry Welch, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - War Department (orders), 1918-19 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Other associates, 1893, 1895, 1905, 1909, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Other correspondence relating to WWI work, 1918-21 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham to various associates, 1918-19, 1921, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
      [see also correspondence in Mary Dows Dunham: Activities: Cooking School for Nurses, box 24]
  - Professional Activities
    - Harvard Medical School
      - Lecture notes
        - Chemistry, 1882-83 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Obstetrics, 1883-84 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Therapeutics, 1883-84 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - "The subtreasury system," 1883 (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - "Abstracts of the physiological action and therapeutic uses of drugs...," 1884 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Papers
        - "History of the Tariff Legislation of the U.S., 1789-1882, " 1883 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - "The circulation," undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Research
      - Cholera research notebooks, 1887, undated (Box 12, Folder 8-11)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Hemophilic infant research, ca. 1908 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Carnaubic acid research, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Research notes on [?], 1908 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Food & calories, 1914-15 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Dichloramine-T, 1916-17 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Antiseptics - notes, charts, 1918-19 (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
      - Empyema
        - Charts for publication, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - Photographs of Army hospitals (VA), 1918 (Box 13, Folder 10-12)
    - Writings
      - "Notes on studies of blood from a hemophilic infant," ca. 1908 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - "The isolation of Carnaubic Acid from beef kidney," 1908 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - "Carnaubin: a phosphatid...," co-authored with Charles A. Jacobson (incomplete manuscript), undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - "The discovery of two new phosphatids, Renatin and Carnaubin," co-authored with Charles A. Jacobson, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - "The discovery..." - additional notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - "The disinfection of drinking water...," co-authored with Dr. Henry D. Dakin, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - "Remarks on Dichloramine-T" (address), ca. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - "Remarks on Dichloramine-T" (pamphlet), 1918 (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - "Report on Meningitis 'carriers' and 'contacts' at Fort Ethan Allen, VT....," 1917 (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - "Antiseptics in the war," (address at Cosmopolitan Club, NYC), 1918, [note: address not by EKD, possibly MKD?] (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - "Antiseptics in the war" (typed manuscript), ca. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - "Cases of Empyema at Camp Lee, VA," 1918 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - "The application of naso-pharyngeal spray to large bodies of troops," (with photographs), 1918 (Box 13, Folder 25-26)
      - untitled (regarding disinfection at an army hospital), undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - untitled (regarding disinfection at an army hospital), undated undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - "On the early histological changes occasioned in normal living animal tissues by some of the commonly employed antiseptics," undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - "[An application to Empyema of] the principles underlying the use of antiseptics," undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - untitled address on Empyema, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - "Observations on chloramines as nasal antiseptics," by Henry D. Dakin & Edward K. Dunham, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Harvey lecture on antiseptics, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - "Infection in the Mediastinum in fulminating cases of Empyema," 1922 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous writings on World War I research, ca. 1918 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Empyema (bound volume), 1924 (Box 14, Folder 10a)
      - Contranct with the Macmillan Company for a Handbook of Antiseptics by Henry D. Dakin and E. K. Dunham 1917 (Box 14, Folder 10b)
    - Related material
      - Printed material relating to World War I, 1918-20 (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous printed material, 1894, 1921, 1914-16, 1923-25, 1931, undated (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
  - Legal
    - Quit claim deeds, 1885 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Partition papers, 1885 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Lease, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Memorabilia
    - Illustrated calendar, 1900 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Verses, greeting cards, miscellaneous, 1895, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - List of "Books in Dr. Dunham's Room," undated (Box 14, Folder 18a)
    - Scrapbook containing correspondence, clippings, ca. 1871-1877 (Box 15)
- Dows Family
  - David Dows 1814-1890
    - Biographical
      - Obituaries, 1890 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Memorial by Rock Island & Pacific Railway Co., 1890 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Biographical sketch by A.E. Orr, 1888 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Articles, 1895, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - "Expressions of sympathy received by the family of David Dows after his death," 1890 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - "Recollections of the late David Dows," by George L. Stebbins, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Memorial scrapbook, ca. 1890 (Box 16)
        [see Oversize materials, box 56]
    - Business correspondence, 1878, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Legal: will, 1888 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Margaret (Worcester) Dows 1831-1909
    - Biographical: obituary, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, family
      - Annie (Dows) Hoe, 1862 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Mary (Dows) Dunham
        - Letters from Europe & the western U.S., 1877, 1880, 1886-90 (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - Letters from Europe, 1891-94 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Letters from Europe & Egypt, 1901-1907, undated (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
        - Edward Kellogg Dunham, 1893-94 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, general
      - Harriet A. Cooke, M.L. Tincker (travelling companions of MDD), 1891-93 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Other correspondence, 1889, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Legal: will, 1906 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      [see also David and Margaret (Worcester) Dows: Silver wedding anniversary album, 1877, in Oversize materials, box 56]
  - Annie (Dows) Hoe (1852-?)
    - Correspondence
      - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1886, 1891-92 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Other correspondence, 1919, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Memorabilia: 50th wedding anniversary verse, by Edward K. Dunham, Jr., 1923 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Margaret (Dows) Dunham 1860-?
    - General correspondence, 1935, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Letter to family from Europe (excerpt), 1922 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Susan (Dows) Dakin (dates unknown): Memorial to first husband, Christian Herter, by Graham Lusk, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - David Dows, Jr. (dates unknown): clippings, flyer, 1936, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Margaret (Dows) Thyberg (dates unknown)
    - Memorabilia
      - Wedding announcement, clippings, ca. 1928 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Photo of Knut Thyberg, undated (Box 16)
      - Diary of Mrs. Richard Montgomery (excerpt), 1820 (Box 16)
- Mary (Dows) Dunham 1865-1936
  - Biographical
    - Biographical and genealogical summary, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, including obituaries, 1936-1938 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Copy of letter describing wedding ceremony, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Writings, [see also EKD, Sr. - Writings]
    - Commonplace book, 1884 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Travel diary - Bermuda, 1886 (Box 17)
    - Travel diary - France, 1891 (Box 17)
    - Family magazine - "Irvington Press," 1890 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Verses, 1895, 1907, 1933, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Verses, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Appointment & address book, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, family
    - Edward & Violet Bodman, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman
      [see also the Bodman Family Papers]
      - Letters, 1903, 1908, 1912, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Letters from France, 1916-17 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
      - Letters, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Henry Dakin, 1922-1924, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Susan (Dows) Dakin, 1927, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - David Dows, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Tracy Dows, 1903, 1920, 1927, 1930 (includes photo) (Box 19, Folder 3b)
    - Beatrice Dunham, 1891, 1895 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Carroll Dunham, Jr., 1891 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr., 1893-1895, 1903, 1918-19, undated (Box 19, Folder 6-16)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr, 1914-15, 1935-36 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Margaret (Dows) Dunham, 1917, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Nancy Yellott Dunham, 1933-1936 (Box 19, Folder 19-20)
    - Theodore & Josephine Dunham, 1896 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Theodore & Miriam Dunham, Jr., 1926-27, 1929, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Amelia Nash (Kellogg) Henshaw, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Herter family, 1893, 1905, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - George L. Stebbins, 1920, 1929-30, 1936 (includes photos) (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Mary & Richard Yellott, 1934, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Other family, 1908, 1924, 1933, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, general
    - John A. Benedict, 1932 (includes photo) (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - [?] Candage, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Bessie Cowtan, 1929, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Cromwell Hall (staff), 1924-25 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Louise Crossette, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Dr. [?] Cussler, 1933 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Hedwig Ehrlich, 1904, undated (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Paul Ehrlich (inc. photo, memorabilia), 1904-14, undated (Box 19, Folder 34a)
    - Dr. William H. Flint, 1896, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Lew Gordon, undated (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Paul Gravenhorst, 1928, 1933, undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Greenwood Cemetery: regarding Dunham plot and headstones, 1923, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 38)
      see also General Family Histories, box 1 and Oversize materials, Flat file
    - Charles W. Parker, 1923 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Antoinette Peterson (includes letters from India), 1906-08, 1922, undated (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
    - Miriam & Theodore Richards, 1917, 1922, 1927, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Abby & John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1924, 1931-32, 1936, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
      [see also Mary (Dows) Dunham, box 24 and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., boxes 28, 30-31]
    - M.L. ("Dorothea") Tincker, 1886-1908, undated (Box 20, Folder 6-22)
  - Correspondence from various people regarding Theodora's speaking war relief work, 1917 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Other correspondence, 1875-1891, 1911, 1913, 1922-29, 1932, 1936, undated (Box 21, Folder 2-5)
  - Correspondence relating to Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr., his work, and the EKD Lectures at Harvard
    [see also Edward Kellogg Dunham, boxes 11-15]
    - Condolence on death of EKD
      - Condolence letters, A-Z, 1922 (Box 21, Folder 6-14)
      - Typed copies of condolence letters (incomplete) & tributes, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
      - Sympathy cards, A-Z, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Condolence telegrams, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Barcroft, 1929, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Walter B. Cannon, 1924, 1930, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Harvey Cushing, 1923, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - D.L. Edsall, 1923, 1924, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Willem Einthoven, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Charles A. Eliot, 1924-25, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Simon Flexner, 1923-24, 1927, 1932-33, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Ulrich Friedemann, 1934-35 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Merritte W. Ireland, 1922, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Franz & Elizabeth Knoop, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence Litchfield, 1924, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - A. Lawrence Lowell, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Graham Lusk, 1922-24, 1926, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Charles Lynch, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - John A. Mandel, 1924, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Otto Lous Mohr, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Warder W. Norton, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Francis Peabody, 1923-24 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Alfred N. Richards, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Frederick Russell, 1922, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Pauline Steffen, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Franklin A. Stevens, 1922, 1926, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Henry Osborne Taylor, 1922 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - William S. Thayer, 1922-23, undated (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - George B. Wallace, 1923, undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - John L. Yates & others regarding EKD's lung model (includes photo), 1924-25 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Hans Zinsser, 1924, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - General correspondence relating to the publication of Empyema, 1922, 1924-27, 1935, undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and lists regarding dispersal of EKD's books and papers, 1924, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Lists of people who received copies of Empyema (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - The Edward Kellogg Dunham Lectures at Harvard
    - General correspondence relating to the EKD Lectures at Harvard, 1923-24, 1927, 1929, 1932-33, 1935, undated (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Other material
      - Gift proposal and background info, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Printed programs, 1924-36 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Articles, clippings, 1923-29, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Activities, general
    - Cooking school for nurses
      - Correspondence, 1919-21, 1924, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Reports on hospitals' food service, 1919-20, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - New York Cooking School: annual reports, 1919, 1923-24 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Barnes Hospital and Simmons College Nursing schools: nutrition course outlines, 1919-24 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Peter Brent Brigham Hospital Nursing School: nutrition course outline, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Recipes & nutritional info., undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Seal Harbor Village Improvement Society: correspondence, reports, 1901, 1904, 1926-27, 1931-32, 1934-35 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - American Red Cross, Mt. Desert Chapter
      - Letters from Charlotte Nelson (public health nurse), 1927, 1929, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1923-24, 1934-37, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Seal Harbor milk supply
      - Correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. & others regarding financing local dairy farm, 1922-36 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Letters from Seal Harbor school children, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Cooksey Realty, Seal Harbor: correspondence, 1927, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Cromwell Hall Health School, Cromwell, CT.: brochure, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Memberships: correspondence, receipts, 1924, 1929, 1933-37 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Donations: correspondence, receipts, 1925, 1929, 1934-36, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Activities, World War I
    [see also correspondence from Theodora (Dunham) Bodman to Mary (Dows) Dunham, box 18, and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., box 27
    and the Bodman Family Papers]
    - American Fund for French Wounded (AFFW)
      - Correspondence
        - Florence C. Bullard (Red Cross nurse in France), 1916-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Polly Herter (AFFW worker) to Susan (Dows) Herter, 1917-18 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - Clara Perry (Theodora's chaperone), 1916-17, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Other AFFW workers, doctors & nurses in France, 1916-19, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - AFFW office in France, 1916-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - American soldiers in France, 1915-17, 1919, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - French wounded soldiers (some letters in French), 1916-19, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Reports from AFFW relief workers in France, 1917, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - New England Branch AFFW: bulletins, monthly reports, 1917-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
      - AFFW relief shipments to France
        - Correspondence, receipts, 1916-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Lists of items sent, 1917-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - Price lists for items sent, 1917-18, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - "Comite Americain pour les Regions Devastees":correspondence, reports, miscellaneous, 1920, 1922, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous World War I material, 1914-15, 1917,undated (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
    - Activities, household
      - Dinner record, 1913-33 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Wedding lists for Theodora (Dunham) and Herbert Bodman, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Wedding announcements, 1893, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Recipes, 1928, 1935, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Recipes for alcoholic beverages, 1921, 1928, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Household inventories, 1918, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Receipts, automobile records, 1930, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - House floor plans for 35 E. 68th Street, New York (N.Y.) and for "Keewaydin," Seal Harbor, (Me.) (Box 26)
      - Tiffany Studio designs (2) (Box 26)
  - Memorabilia
    - Writings by Theodora (Dunham) Bodman for MDD, 1913 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Verses to MDD, 1891, 1896, 1905, 1915, 1921, 1925-26, 1927, 1929, 1934, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous verses, 1907, 1913, 1918, 1927, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Invitations, 1924-35, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Simon Flexner/Rockefeller Institute Medal, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1922, 1935, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1893, 1927, 1932, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1896, 1925, 1931-34, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Artwork - stencils, sketches, watercolors, 1883-84 (Box 26)
    [see Oversize material, box 55]
- Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr. (1901-1951)
  - Biographical: obituaries, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    [see also Nancy (Yellott) Dunham: correspondence: condolence letters, box 32]
  - Writings
    - Description of European trip (with writings by (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Verses, 1921, 1923, 1927, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, family
    - Edward Bodman, 1927-34, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Herbert Bodman, Jr., 1929, 1931-32 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman, 1912-17, 1919, 1927, 1929-30, 1933-34, undated (Box 27, Folder 6-8)
    - Violet Bodman, 1927, 1929, 1931-32, 1938, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Henry D. Dakin, 1920-22, 1936, 1940-42, 1946-47, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Susan (Dows) Dakin, 1937, 1940, 1945, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Edward Kellogg Dunham, Sr., 1912-1915, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Edward K. Dunham III, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1914, 1923-27, undated (includes photos) (Box 27, Folder 14-20)
    - Mary (Dows) Dunham, 1928-34, undated (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - Nancy (Yellott) Dunham, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Harper Dunham, 1950-51, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Yellott family, 1935-36, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Other family, 1926, 1930-31, 1934, 1936, 1946, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, general
    - Herbert Carter, 1917, 1927, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Miss Maxon (secretary) regarding Anne (Dows) Hoe, 1938-40 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Theodore W. Richards, 1918, 1921 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1926 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      [see also Mary (Dows) Dunham, boxes 20 & 24 and Edward Kellogg Dunham, Jr., boxes 30-31
    - Condolence letters on MDD's death, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Other correspondence, 1914, 1920-21, 1926, 1928-30, 1933, 1937-38, 1940, 1944, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Professional and Financial Activities
    - Corn Exchange Bank: brochure, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - U.S. By-Products Corporation: correspondence, 1927-28, undated (Box 29)
    - Dows Estates, Inc.
      - Correspondence, 1914-15, 1934, 1938-39,1944-46 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Financial statements, legal documents, 1939, 1944-45 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Mary (Dows) Dunham estate
      - Correspondence
        - Paul G. Gravenhorst (attorney), 1938-40 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Herbert L. Bodman, Carroll Dunham, III (& others), 1933-35, 1938-40, 1948-50 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Legal documents, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Financial statements, 1936, 1938-40 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Financial statements of account with Dows Estates', 1939-42, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Artwork: correspondence, inventories, 1941, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - House: clipping, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Theodora (Dunham) Bodman trust: account statements, 1938-41, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Balch-McMahon trust: correspondence, account figures, 1930, 1938-41, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Ann (Dows) Hoe estate: correspondence, 1938-39 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Activities, general
    - Students' Army Training Corps: schedule,regulations, 1918, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - American Fund for French Wounded: report,correspondence from French soldiers, 1917-18 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      [see also Mary (Dows) Dunham, box 25]
    - Seal Harbor Village Improvement Society:report, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - American Red Cross, Mount Desert Chapter
      [see also Mary (Dows) Dunham, box 24]
      - Fund drive receipts, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Reports, miscellaneous printed matter, 1936-38, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Seal Harbor Committee for Fire Protection
      - Correspondence, 1930-31 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Reports, plans, miscellaneous material, 1930-32, undated (includes photos) (Box 30, Folder 7)